JOSHUA T. GUERIN | Curriculum Vitae

✓ jguerin@utm.edu • Martin, TN • J (859) 576-2726
GitHub • In LinkedIn • G Facebook

SUMMARY & SKILLS

Computer Science Professor • Al Specialist • Competitive Strongman

SPECIALIZED SKILLS Answer Set Programming | Knowledge Representation and Reasoning

Logic Foundations of Al | Logical & Functional Programming | SAT Solvers **PROGRAMMING LANGUAGE**Experienced: C | C++ | Clingo (Answer-Set Dialect) | Haskell | Java | Python

Familiar: Javascript | Lisp | Matlab | Perl | PHP | Prolog | R | Shell Scripting | SQL

FRAMEWORKS & TOOLS Docs Generators | Git | Graphviz/DOT Language | MTFX Unix CLI

2012

EDUCATION _____

UNIVERSITY OF KENTUCKY Lexington, KY UNIVE

Ph.D., Computer Science

<u>Dissertation</u>

Graphical Models for Decision Support in Academic Advising.

Relevant Coursework

Algorithm Design | Artificial Intelligence | Bayesian Al Boolean Functions | Data Mining | Intermediate Database Systems | Declarative Programming Programming Languages

M.S., Computer Science 2010
Graduate Certificate, Cognitive Science 2009

TRANSYLVANIA UNIVERSITY
B.A., Computer Science

Minor: Psychology

Lexington, KY

Experience _____

UNIVERSITY OF TENNESSEE AT MARTIN
Professor
Department Chair
Interim Department Chair
Associate Professor

Assistant Professor

UNIVERSITY OF TENNESSEE AT MARTIN
Acrtin, TN
2021-present
2018-2021
2017-2018
2016-2021
2012-2016

UNIVERSITY OF KENTUCKY
Research Fellowship
Lexington Herald-Leader Research Fellowship

TRANSYLVANIA UNIVERSITYPart-Time Instructor

Lexington, KY
Fall 2011

UNIVERSITY OF KENTUCKY
Teaching & Research Assistant

Lexington, KY
2007-2011

Example courses taught _____

UNIVERSITY OF TENNESSEE AT MARTIN

2012-Present

Algorithm Design and Analysis • Artificial Intelligence • Intro to C++
Autonomous Mobile Robotics • Computer Graphics • Data Structures
Discrete Mathematics • Microcontrollers Lab • Object-Oriented Programming
Programming Language Paradigms • Senior Capstone Project/Career Preparation
Theory of Computation • Quantum Programming

EXAMPLE HONORS & AWARDS

UNIVERSITY OF TENNESSEE AT MARTIN

2012-Present

- UT Alumni Association Outstanding Teaching Award
- College of Engineering and Natural Sciences Ray and Wilma Smith Professorship
- ACM Mid-Southeast Conference, 3rd Place (Undergraduate Award Faculty Mentor) "Using Genetic Algorithms to Approximate Digital Circuits."
- ASEE Zone 1 Conference Professional Paper Award Nominee Lessons Learned from Development of a Software Tool to Support Academic Advising."